polaroideyewear.com 2019-06-30

# Privacy Policy | Polaroid

This policy shows the methods and purposes of the processing carried out by Safilo S.p.A.,  with headquarters in Settima Strada 15, 35129 Padova, Italy, Ph.+39 049 698 5111 (hereinafter,  **"Safilo"** ), as Data Controller, of the personal data of the subjects involved in respect of the browsing of the website [www.polaroideyewear.com](http://www.polaroideyewear.com/). ( **“Site”** ) on the occasion of your access to the Site, as well as the necessary information about your rights and how to exercise them.

  The processing of visitor's data by Safilo will be based on the principles of transparency, correctness, lawfulness, relevance and necessity. 

  The appointed Data Protection Officer ("DPO") can be contacted at the e-mail [dpo@safilo.com](mailto:dpo@safilo.com)  
.  
**What kind of information do we collect, for what purposes and with which legal basis?**

 _1) Navigation data_

  Computer systems responsible for site operation acquire, during normal operation, some personal data that are implicit in the use of Internet communication protocols.  This information is not collected to be associated with identified persons, but only for the legitimate interest of the site owner in the safe system operation and to ensure visitors the navigation on the site. By their very nature such data could, through processing and association with data held by third parties, allow users to be identified.  This category of data includes IP addresses or domain names of computers used by users who connect to the site, the URI (Uniform Resource Identifier) addresses of the requested resources, the time of request, the method used to submit the request to the server, the size of the file obtained in reply, the numerical code indicating the status of the response given by the server (successful, error, etc.) and other parameters relating to the user's operating system and computer environment.   The data could be used by police forces and judicial authorities upon request for the performance of their duties. 

  The data will be used exclusively for the safe operation of the systems and to ensure the visitor the navigation on the site, thus constituting the contractual and pre-contractual implementation of this processing.

 _2) Data delivered voluntarily by visitors_

  These data are provided spontaneously by visitors to take advantage of the interactive activities offered by the Site.  In particular, Safilo may request personal information in some sections of the site, such as name, surname, address, date of birth, sex, email address, etc. This may happen, for example, if you purchase products, sign up for a contest, competition or promotion, send a message from the Contact Us section and in order to get services that require a registration or subscription. 

  Except where not otherwise indicated, the personal data supplied will be used exclusively to manage and respond to the requests of the user/visitor, thus constituting the contractual and pre-contractual implementation of this processing.

  In each of the above-mentioned sections of the Site where personal data are collected for each different purposes, there are specific Privacy policies explaining the details of the processings, as well as any requests for consent to the processing of personal data for marketing and even profiled purposes (for more details click here), for which the specific consents are the legal basis of the processings.  

  The user/visitor is in any case asked to refrain from entering special categories of personal data, i.e. those that reveal racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical convictions, or union membership, as well as processing genetic data, biometric data intended to uniquely identify a natural person, data related to the health or sex life or sexual orientation of the person, since they cannot be treated further without consent and must be eliminated.

 _3) Cookies_

  We may also use cookies to collect information regarding the visits to our site and to improve the browsing experience.  More information on the use of cookies can be found in the Policy Cookie.

  **Kind of the data provision and consequences of refusal  **

  The provision of personal data above by users/visitors is automatic (therefore, mandatory) in the case of browsing the site for navigation data, optional for data provided voluntarily (see also the Cookie Policy for cookies). However, failure to give optional data will result in the impossibility of being able to enjoy certain functionalities of the Site and the requested activities. Instead, failure to give your consents to the use of your data by Safilo for the purposes of profiled and/or generalized direct marketing will not affect in any way the functionalities of the Site and the requested activities, but will not allow Safilo to transmit you the marketing communications referred to above.

  **Processing methods and subjects who may have access to data**

  Personal data are processed with electronic instruments for the time necessary to achieve the purposes for which they were collected.  They are processed in compliance with the applicable legislation, adopting the appropriate and most suitable security measures aimed at preventing unauthorized access, disclosure, modification or unauthorized destruction.  
Data will be processed by Safilo employees or collaborators, specifically trained on the treatment and any digital service providers appointed as data controllers.  
Data will not be disclosed to third parties except for legal obligations or judicial authorities and will not be disseminated in any way.

  **Data retention time**

  We keep personal data voluntarily provided by visitors only for the time strictly necessary for the execution of the requested service, in case of consent to marketing activities up to 36 months after the provision of the relative consent and, in case of purchases through the site, for 10 years from their collection for any legal protection requirements.  We keep browsing data for 30 days.  
. 

  **Rights  **

  It will be possible at any time to exercise access to one's personal data, correct, integrate or delete them or request the limitation of processing that concerns the ones pending correction or the end necessary to protect the rights, object to the processing, revoke the consents given, and also obtain (in case of consent to the processing) the release, in electronic form, to oneself or to another person indicated, of the personal data provided, sending a written request to the e-mail address [dataprotection@safilo.com](mailto:dataprotection@safilo.com).  
You will also always have the right to lodge a complaint regarding the processing of your personal data to the competent Supervisory Authority (the Guarantor for the Protection of Personal Data in Italy).

  **Link to third parties**

  For convenience and to improve the use of the website we insert links to third party sites and plug-ins to the main social networks, which are not covered by this privacy policy.  These links and plug-ins go beyond our service and the website, Safilo, and we do not exercise any control over them.  This includes links to partners that may use Safilo logos as part of a co-branding agreement or may sell Safilo products. The sites to which you can access through said  links and plug-ins have their own privacy policy and, as much as we try to protect the integrity of our site, Safilo declines any and all liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. The user will visit, and will, therefore, access such sites at his own discretion and under his responsibility.  These sites may send their own cookies to users, collect data or ask for personal information.

  **Information notice amendments**

  We may from time to time make changes to this disclosure imposed by changes in legislation and to stay abreast of new developments and possibilities on Internet. We reserve the right to make such changes at our discretion; the user is periodically asked to check this page, as it is subject to such changes when you visit our website.
